cfr.org 2017-11-20

# Privacy Policy | Council on Foreign Relations

_Effective date: April 2017_

Welcome to [www.cfr.org](http://www.cfr.org/), published by Council on Foreign Relations (CFR), (collectively “we”, “us” or “ours”). We respect your privacy and we are committed to handle fairly the personal information you provide to us. This Privacy Policy describe the types of information we may collect from you, as well as our practices for collecting, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information. This Policy applies to your use of [www.cfr.org](http://www.cfr.org/) and our mobile applications (“Sites”).

By visiting our Sites, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy, including our use of cookies and similar online tools. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. If you continue to use our Sites after changes have been made to the terms, you are accepting those changes.

## Information We Collect

When you visit our Sites, we may collect two types of information: personal information and non-personal information. Personal information is any information that can individually identify you and includes, but is not limited to, your name, address and email address. We only collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us. We also collect non-personal information through third-party technology including tracking and usage information about your location demographics, and use of our Sites.

## Personal Information

You may browse the Sites without submitting your personal information to us. However, in order to access some features on the website you may need to provide us with personal information such as your name, e-mail address or other identifying information.

Personal information is collected when you subscribe to one of CFR’s newsletters, register as a member, make a gift, and/or sign up for the press list.

## Non-Personal Information

When you use the Site, we may log or track some usage information that does not identify you, such as your IP address, general location information, unique device identifier, browser type, and language. We may also collect information about your use of our Sites, including your search terms, search results, and additional traffic data such as time and date of access, software crash reports, and session identification number.

## “Cookies” and Other Tracking Technology

We use “cookies,” web beacons, HTML 5 local storage and other similar tracking technologies. These technologies track your use of our Sites and online services and make it easier and/or more relevant for your use. They also help us monitor traffic and continually improve the Sites. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you may modify your browser setting to disable or reject cookies. If you set your web browser to decline cookies or if you delete your cookies, some features of the Sites may not work or may not work as designed.

## How We Use Information 

We use the information we learn from you to help improve your experience on the Sites. The information helps us provide you with the content and services that you request, communicate with you about your subscription or registration, personalize your experience on the Sites by recommending specific content, send you newsletters, continually improve our Sites, and perform statistical and demographic analyses of users of the Sites.

We may share personal information with our contractors and service providers in order to maintain, enhance, or add to the functionality of our services.

We will not sell, rent, or otherwise share personal information to a party outside CFR and its affiliates or its service providers except as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Newsletters Opt-Out

If at any time you no longer prefer to receive electronic newsletters and/or other emails, you may opt out of receiving them by following the “unsubscribe” instructions included in each newsletter email.

## Links to Third Party Sites and Services

We have third party agents that perform functions on our behalf, including but not limited to, hosting, content management tools, social media integration, analytics, billing and applications tracking services. These entities may have access to personal information if needed to perform their functions. If such access is required, the third parties will be obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that personal information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Sites.

## Legal Disclaimer

In some cases, we may use or disclose your personal information to a third party if we are required to do so by law, to prevent misuse of Sites, or to protect our personal safety or that of others.

## How Do We Protect Your Information?

We take reasonable security measures to protect your information, including the use of physical, technical and administrative controls. When stored, passwords are encrypted and are not recoverable. We use SSL when we transmit personal information, and such information is encrypted in transit. While we use our best efforts to safeguard your personal information once we receive it, any transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network carries risk. As such, you should take precautions to protect the security of any personal information that you may transmit over any home networks, wireless routers, wireless (Wi-Fi) networks or similar devices by using encryption and other techniques to prevent unauthorized persons from intercepting or receiving any of your personal information. You are responsible for the security of your information when using unencrypted, open access, or otherwise unsecured networks.

## Governing Law and Notice to Non-U.S. Users

The Sites are published in the United States and comply with all applicable laws of our jurisdictions. If you are uncertain whether this Privacy Policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your personal information to CFR.

 If you are located outside the United States, you should be aware that any personal information that you provide will be transferred to and stored in the United States. By using our Sites, you consent to such transmission and to use of your personal information in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We will take steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal information is treated securely, but will not otherwise take steps to ensure that compliance with applicable laws in each user’s country of residence.

## Children Under the Age of Thirteen

The Sites are not intended for children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 years of age. If you are under thirteen years of age, do not provide personal information to us without providing us with personal consent from your parents. If we become aware that a child under the age of thirteen has provided us with personal information and we do not have parental consent, we will immediately delete that child’s information from the Sites. If you believe that we have been provided with the personal information of a child under the age of thirteen without parental consent, please notify us immediately at [webmaster@cfr.org](mailto:webmaster@cfr.org).

## Terms of Use

Please visit our Terms and Conditions to learn about the use, disclaimers and liability governing the use of our site. 

## Access to Personal Information

If you want your personal information to be updated, corrected or removed you may do so by emailing us at [webmaster@cfr.org](mailto:webmaster@cfr.org) or contacting us by mail at the address below.

## Questions?

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us through the following channels:

Email: [webmaster@cfr.org](mailto:webmaster@cfr.org)

Postal Services:  
Council on Foreign Relations  
Attn: General Counsel  
58 East 68th Street  
New York, NY 10065
